<div style="font-family: Verdana; font-size:11px">

<link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="${root-url}mixter-files/home.css" title="Default Style"/>   

<h1>JamGlue and ccMixter</h1>

<div style="width: 70%; margin-left: 10%;">
    <div id="fs_container">
     <table id="fs_table" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" >
       <tr><td id="fs_top_left" /><td id="fs_top">&nbsp;</td><td id="fs_top_right" /></tr>
       <tr><td id="fs_side" />
           <td id="fs_content">

<div style="float: right; margin: 8px;" ><a href="http://jamglue.com/"><img src="${root-url}mixter-files/jamglue.gif" /></a></div>
<p>We are proud to welcome <a href="http://jamglue.com/">JamGlue</a> to the Creative Commons 
Sample Pool. JamGlue's mission is to provide "Remxing for the Masses" by allowing anybody to try their hand
at remixing right in the comfort of their browser. Sites like JamGlue are an important step in giving music back to 
the people that matter the most: all of us. (JamGlue is not officially affiliated with Creative Commons or ccMixter,
we're just think they are cool and want to use their samples.)
</p>
            </td>
          <td id="fs_side" />
        </tr>
       <tr><td id="fs_bot_left" /><td id="fs_bot">&nbsp;</td><td id="fs_bot_right" /></tr>
    </table>
    </div>

<h3 style="text-align: left">Remixers at JamGlue</h3>

<p>Members of JamGlue are encouraged to create their remixes
directly on their site using original source material from either their site or.... (<a 
href="http://ccmixter.org/media/files/tazzista/6590">drum roll)</a> here at ccMixter. When a JamGlue remix uses 
sources from here our 'Samples are used in' field will reflect the remix with a link to it...
</p>
<p style="text-align:center"><img src="${root-url}mixter-files/jamglue-1.png" /></p>



<h3 style="text-align: left">Remixers at ccMixter</h3>

<p>Not only does JamGlue host remixes made on their website, but they have a pretty 
<a href="http://www.jamglue.com/people/fridge">amazing sample collection</a> as well. Here at ccMixter
we've added JamGlue to the remix upload form's search capability so you can use their samples
in remixes posted here. See the <a href="{$root-url}freesound">freesound page</a> for how to
properly attribute samples that come from another sample pool.</p>
</div>

</div>
  